Guide to "Africa Album" - A trip across northern Algeria AD.MC.063
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
"Africa Album" - A trip across northern Algeria
Circa 1912-1920
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.063
150 Photographic Prints
Photographic Prints; Algeria
- The front cover of "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref1; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Algeria
- The inside front cover of "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref2; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
- A blank page in "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref3; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
- A blank page in "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref4; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
- A colored lithographed map of North West Africa, including Morocco, Tunisia, and Algeria., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref5; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  North Africa; Maps; English Writing
- From the top left clockwise: two men on a ship, two views of the Santa Cruz Church, the Port of Oran, a view of Habibas Island, a building by the coast, and an aerial view of Oran., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref6; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Group Portraits; Hats; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Gelatin Silver Prints; Cigarettes; Smoking; Facial Hair; Churches; Religious Sites; Ports; Oran, Algeria; Statues/Sculptures; Water; Seas; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes
- Landscapes on the way from Oran to Tipaza., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref7; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Oran, Algeria; Algeria; Transportation; Countryside/Rural; Trains; Buildings; Railways
- Six views of the same mountain on the way from Oran to Tipaza., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref8; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Countryside/Rural; Railways; Trains; Transportation; Water; Algeria; Oran, Algeria; Landscapes
- Hills on the way from Oran to Tipaza, including a view of the railway tracks., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref9; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Railways; Transportation; Trains; Countryside/Rural; Oran, Algeria; Algeria; Landscapes; Streets/Roads
- From the top down: group portraits of men and children, a woman leading a donkey, and two views inside a barn in Tipaza., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref10; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Streets/Roads; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; Animals; Agriculture/Farms; Donkeys; Canes/Walking Sticks; Buildings; Machines; Countryside/Rural; Workers; Algeria
- From the top left clockwise: a man shaving another man's head, a man next to a carriage for the Grand Hotel des Bains Hammam Birha, a child in a rural setting, a woman holding a bottle, and a man spraying crops., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref11; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Group Portraits; Countryside/Rural; Electricity; Agriculture/Farms; Hats; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Canes/Walking Sticks; Palm Trees; Boys; Children; Regional/National Dress; Women; Alcohol; Drinks/Beverages; Tobacco pipes; Smoking; Springs; Hotels; Tipaza, Algeria; French Writing
- From the top left clockwise: a horse, a group of people near a clock tower, a man with two horses, boys and men at a campsite, and a group of men in uniform., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref12; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Animals; Crowds; Clocks/Watches; Men; Group Portraits; Hats; Smoking; Cigarettes; Streets/Roads; Signs/Signposts; Palm Trees; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Tents; Boys; Children; Mountains/Hills; Donkeys; Countryside/Rural; Uniforms; Tipaza, Algeria
- From the top left clockwise: a man next to a horse, and three views of hills on the to the ruins of Tipasa [Tipaza]., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref13; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Men; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; Forest/Woodlands; Countryside/Rural; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Landscapes; Animals; Facial Hair; Canes/Walking Sticks; Tipaza, Algeria
- Views of hills, bridges, farms, and the coast on the way to the ruins of Tipasa [Tipaza]. Including a view of the Basilica of St. Crispinus in the top right corner., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref14; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Mountains/Hills; Countryside/Rural; Agriculture/Farms; Landscapes; Tipaza, Algeria; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Coast; Bridges
- The Roman ruins in Tipasa [Tipaza] including the Basilica of St. Salsa and a leaning tomb., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref15; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings; Countryside/Rural; Landscapes; Tombs/Mausoleums; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Tipaza, Algeria; English Writing; French Writing
- Views of the Royal Mausoleum of Mauretania (Tombeau de la Chrétienne/Kubr-er-Rumia) and surrounding artefacts., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref16; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tipaza, Algeria; English Writing; French Writing; Architecture; Countryside/Rural; Cemeteries; Palm Trees
- Landscapes with views of railway tracks on the way from Tipaza to Constantine., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref17; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Bridges; Streets/Roads; Water; Countryside/Rural; Mountains/Hills; Railways; Trains; Transportation; Algeria; Tunnels
- From the top left clockwise: a group of people gathered around a monkey (an advertisement for Liqueur du Père Kermann, F. Cazanove is in the background), street scenes showing monkeys, and three views of bridges in Constantine, Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref18; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Advertisements; Alcohol; Animals; Men; Streets/Roads; Hats; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; Women; Facial Hair; Buildings; Fur Garments; Bridges; Mountains/Hills; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Hotels; Constantine, Algeria
- From the top left clockwise: monkeys beside a bridge, a bridge, a mountain view, and a man standing below a waterfall, Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref19; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Animals; Bridges; Mountains/Hills; Countryside/Rural; Men; Hats; Canes/Walking Sticks; Individual Portraits; Landscapes; Constantine, Algeria; Waterfalls; Water; Rivers
- Views of Constantine, including the Sidi Rached Viaduct (Pont Sidi Rached)., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref20; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bridges; Buildings; Constantine, Algeria; Architecture; Coast; Water; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills
- Views of Constantine and the plateau it sits on, including a railway tunnel that passes through the mountain., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref21; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Architecture; Constantine, Algeria; Bridges; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Tunnels; Railways; Transportation; Trains
- Views of the ravine near Constantine, including views of the city and various bridges including the Sidi M'Cid Bridge, the Bridge of Sidi Rached, and the Pont Bab El Kantara., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref22; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Bridges; Constantine, Algeria; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Landscapes
- From the top left clockwise: buildings in Constantine, a camp in the city, the Rhummel Gorge, a view of a landscape, two views of men in the courtyard of a building, and view of a landscape, Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref23; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Tents; Men; Children; Regional/National Dress; Water; Mountains/Hills; Individual Portraits; Sheep; Animals; Landscapes; Countryside/Rural; Markets; Crowds; Streets/Roads; Rivers; Constantine, Algeria
- Views of the Roman ruins in Timgad, including Trajan's Arch., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref24; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Mountains/Hills; Architecture; Timgad, Batna province, Algeria
- From the top left clockwise: two views of a railway going through mountains, mountains, a child standing next to a donkey and a man posing at the Roman ruins in Timgad., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref25; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Railways; Mountains/Hills; Transportation; Trains; Palm Trees; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats; Books; Clocks/Watches; Children; Regional/National Dress; Donkeys; Agriculture/Farms; Timgad, Batna province, Algeria
- Views of Algeria, including a performance (top left) streets, farms, and crowds., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref26; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Palm Trees; Crowds; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads; Electricity; Architecture; Umbrellas/Parasols; Algeria
- Seven portraits of Algerians. Top right and top left views feature the Hotel Palace., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref27; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Donkeys; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Facial Hair; Men; Palm Trees; Camels; Hotels; English Writing; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Women; Children; Deserts; Streets/Roads; Algeria
- Top Row: a portrait of two men and two women, and four donkeys. Middle Row: portraits of women riding horses, and four donkeys. Bottom Row: two men farming, and a man riding a horse., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref28; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Canes/Walking Sticks; Facial Hair; Palm Trees; Horses; Tents; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Individual Portraits; Agriculture/Farms; Donkeys; Animals; Workers; Algeria
- Top Row: street scenes. Middle Row: three views of an Algerian town. Bottom: a portrait of a woman and two men, and a street scene., Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref29; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Children; Boys; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Goats; Donkeys; Animals; Palm Trees; Architecture; Women; Hats; Facial Hair; Algeria
- The inside back cover of "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref30; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
- The back cover of "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref31; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
- The spine of "Africa Album.", Circa 1912-1920; AD_MC_063_ref32; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_063)
  Algeria; English Writing